{
    "overview": "Overview",
    "overview-title": "Things to Know | L'Hexagone",
    "language": "Language",
    "language-title": "Language Tips | L'Hexagone",
    "travel": "Travel",
    "travel-title": "Travel Tips | L'Hexagone",

    "overview-elements": [
        {
            "id": "1",
            "title": "Daily Schedule",
            "content": "<ul><li>Shops and restaurants often close at midday (around 12–2pm)</li><li>Many shops and services are closed on Sundays</li><li>Mealtimes are later than in some countries — dinner typically starts after 7:30pm</li></ul>"
        },

        {
            "id": "2",
            "title": "Money and Shopping",
            "content": "<ul><li>France uses the Euro (€)</li><li>Contactless cards are widely accepted, but some places still prefer cash</li><li>Sales only happen twice a year (winter and summer) — “Les Soldes”</li><li>Bring your own bag — plastic bags often cost extra or aren’t provided</li><li>It’s normal to weigh your own produce at supermarkets using a machine</li></ul>"
        },

        {
            "id": "3",
            "title": "Public Facilities",
            "content": "<ul><li>Public toilets may require payment or have odd opening times</li><li>Tourist information centres are helpful for local advice, free maps and event details</li><li>Tap water is safe to drink — look for free water fountains in public spaces</li><li>Libraries often provide free Wi-Fi and quiet spaces to relax</li></ul>"
        },

        {
            "id": "4",
            "title": "Health and Emergencies",
            "content": "<ul><li>Pharmacies are marked with a green cross</li><li>There is always an emergency pharmacy open in each area, even on Sundays</li><li>You can call 112 for emergencies across the EU</li></ul>"
        },

        {
            "id": "5",
            "title": "Culture and Social Norms",
            "content": "<ul><li>It's customary to greet people with \"Bonjour\" (hello) or \"Bonsoir\" (good evening) when entering shops or restaurants</li><li>Tipping in cafés and restaurants is appreciated but not mandatory</li><li>France is officially secular — religious symbols are banned in public schools and institutions</li></ul>"
        },

        {
            "id": "6",
            "title": "Dining Etiquette",
            "content": "<ul><li>It's customary to keep your hands visible on the table, resting your wrists on the edge of your plate</li><li>Don't start eating until everyone at the table has been served</li><li>Many French people take their time over meals — it's a social event, not just about eating</li><li>It’s common to ask for \"l'addition\" (the bill) when you're ready to leave, as it won't be automatically brought to the table</li></ul>"
        }
    ],

    "common-signs": "Common Signs",
    "french": "French",
    "current-language-capital": "English",
    "learn": "Learn",
    "practise": "Practise",
    "exit": "Exit",
    "entrance": "Entrance",
    "checkout": "Checkout",
    "toilets": "Toilets",
    "forbidden": "Forbidden",
    "open": "Open",
    "closed": "Closed",
    "push": "Push",
    "pull": "Pull",
    "no-smoking": "No Smoking",
    "no-entry": "No Entry",
    "emergency-exit": "Emergency Exit",
    "opening-hours": "Opening Hours",

    "back": "Back",
    "next": "Next",
    "common-signs-terms": [
        {
            "id": 1,
            "front": "Sortie",
            "back": "Exit"
        },

        {
            "id": 2,
            "front": "Entrée",
            "back": "Entrance"
        },

        {
            "id": 3,
            "front": "Caisse",
            "back": "Checkout"
        },

        {
            "id": 4,
            "front": "Toilettes",
            "back": "Toilets"
        },

        {
            "id": 5,
            "front": "Interdit",
            "back": "Forbidden"
        },

        {
            "id": 6,
            "front": "Ouvert",
            "back": "Open"
        },

        {
            "id": 7,
            "front": "Fermé",
            "back": "Closed"
        },

        {
            "id": 8,
            "front": "Poussez",
            "back": "Push"
        },

        {
            "id": 9,
            "front": "Tirez",
            "back": "Pull"
        },

        {
            "id": 10,
            "front": "Défense de fumer",
            "back": "No Smoking"
        },

        {
            "id": 11,
            "front": "Accès interdit",
            "back": "No Entry"
        },

        {
            "id": 12,
            "front": "Issue de secours",
            "back": "Emergency Exit"
        },

        {
            "id": 13,
            "front": "Horaires d'ouverture",
            "back": "Opening Hours"
        }
    ],

    "useful-phrases": "Useful Phrases",
    "hello": "Hello",
    "good-evening": "Good evening",
    "hi": "Hi",
    "goodbye": "Goodbye",
    "thank-you": "Thank you",
    "thank-you-very-much": "Thank you very much",
    "youre-welcome": "You're welcome",
    "please": "Please",
    "excuse-me": "Excuse me",
    "sorry": "Sorry",
    "i-would-like": "I would like...",
    "do-you-have": "Do you have...?",
    "where-is": "Where is...?",
    "where-are-the-toilets": "Where are the toilets?",
    "help": "Help!",
    "current-language": "anglais",
    "do-you-speak": "Do you speak English?",
    "useful-phrases-terms": [
        {
            "id": 1,
            "front": "Bonjour",
            "back": "Hello"
        },

        {
            "id": 2,
            "front": "Bonsoir",
            "back": "Good evening"
        },

        {
            "id": 3,
            "front": "Salut",
            "back": "Hi"
        },

        {
            "id": 4,
            "front": "Au revoir",
            "back": "Goodbye"
        },

        {
            "id": 5,
            "front": "Merci",
            "back": "Thank you"
        },

        {
            "id": 6,
            "front": "Merci beaucoup",
            "back": "Thank you very much"
        },

        {
            "id": 7,
            "front": "De rien",
            "back": "You're welcome"
        },

        {
            "id": 8,
            "front": "S'il vous plaît",
            "back": "Please"
        },

        {
            "id": 9,
            "front": "Excusez-moi",
            "back": "Excuse me"
        },

        {
            "id": 10,
            "front": "Je suis désolé(e)",
            "back": "Sorry"
        },

        {
            "id": 11,
            "front": "Je voudrais...",
            "back": "I would like..."
        },

        {
            "id": 12,
            "front": "Avez-vous... ?",
            "back": "Do you have...?"
        },

        {
            "id": 13,
            "front": "Où est... ?",
            "back": "Where is...?"
        },

        {
            "id": 14,
            "front": "Où sont les toilettes ?",
            "back": "Where are the toilets?"
        },

        {
            "id": 15,
            "front": "Au secours !",
            "back": "Help!"
        },

        {
            "id": 16,
            "front": "Parlez-vous anglais ?",
            "back": "Do you speak English?"
        }
    ],

    "punctuation": "Punctuation",
    "punctuation-text": "In French, punctuation works a little differently. Sometimes, a narrow space is used before a punctuation mark. Often French people use a normal, full space for general conversation, only using the narrow space in formal documents or media. You would use a narrow space before these punctuation marks:",
    "semi-colon": "semi-colon ( ;)",
    "exclamation-mark": "exclamation mark ( !)",
    "question-mark": "question mark ( ?)",
    "colon": "colon ( :)",
    "quotation-marks": "quotation marks ( « and » in French)",
    "percentage-sign": "percentage sign ( %)",
    "currency-symbols": "currency symbols (eg. €)",

    
    "travel-elements": [
        {
            "id": "1",
            "title": "Customs and Visas",
            "content": "<ul><li>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit, sed do eiusmod</li><li>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor incididunt ut labore et dolore magna aliqua</li><li>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit</li></ul>"
        },

        {
            "id": "2",
            "title": "Flights",
            "content": "<ul><li>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit, sed do eiusmod</li><li>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor incididunt ut labore et dolore magna aliqua</li><li>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit</li></ul>"
        },

        {
            "id": "3",
            "title": "Trains",
            "content": "<ul><li><a href='https://www.eurail.com/en/eurail-passes/one-country-pass/france' target='_blank' rel='noreferrer'>Get a Eurail Pass</a></li><li>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit, sed do eiusmod</li><li>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor incididunt ut labore et dolore magna aliqua</li></ul>"
        },

        {
            "id": "4",
            "title": "Accessible Travel",
            "content": "<ul><li>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit, sed do eiusmod</li><li>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor incididunt ut labore et dolore magna aliqua</li><li>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit</li></ul>"
        }
    ]
}